Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Goldfarb Consultants Ford Research Reports, 1974-1989
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Goldfarb Consultants Ford Research Reports 1974-1989
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office.
2.4 Linear Feet 1800 Items
The J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT), founded in 1864, is one of the largest and oldest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Goldfarb Consultants, founded in 1966 by Canadian pollster and market researcher Martin Goldfarb, is a leading Canadian marketing consulting group that specializes in focus groups and other qualitative research methods. Martin Goldfarb sold his interest in Goldfarb Consultants to JWT's parent company, WPP, in 1998.
The Goldfarb Consultants Ford Research Reports span the years 1974 to 1989 and consist of written research summaries primarily of advertising campaigns for various Ford automobiles, vans, and trucks. In addition there are reports on a range of specialized consumer markets, focused on women, African-American, Hispanic, youth, college-age consumer groups as well as some reports on regional markets.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office. Goldfarb Consultants Ford Research Reports were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 2002.
Biographical Note
The J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT), founded in 1864, is one of the largest and oldest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Goldfarb Consultants, founded in 1966 by Canadian pollster and market researcher Martin Goldfarb, is a leading Canadian marketing consulting firm that specializes in focus groups and other qualitative research methods. Martin Goldfarb sold his interest in Goldfarb Consultants to JWT's parent company, WPP, in 1998.
Collection Overview
The Goldfarb Consultants Ford Research Reports span the years 1974 to 1989 and consist of written research summaries primarily of advertising campaigns for various Ford automobiles, vans, and trucks. In addition there are reports on a range of specialized consumer markets, focused on women, African-American, Hispanic, youth, college-age consumer groups as well as some reports on regional markets.
The collection is arranged into two self-evident series: Consumer Research, and Ford Motor Company Studies. The Consumer Research Series is organized alphabetically by topic. The Ford Motor Company Studies Series is organized alphabetically by automobile model name.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
J. Walter Thompson Company
J. Walter Thompson Company -- Detroit Office
Ford Motor Company
Goldfarb Consultants
Advertising -- Automobiles
Advertising -- Automobiles -- United States
Advertising -- Automobiles -- United States -- Case studies
Advertising -- Research
Ford automobile -- Marketing
Marketing research
Qualitative research -- Methodology
Research reports and papers
African-American consumers
Hispanic-American consumers. American
Consumers -- United States
Teenage consumers -- United States
Women consumers
Women consumers -- United States
Young consumers
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Contents of Collection
- Consumer Research Series, 1980-1986, (1 box)
  - General, 1980-1986 (Box 1)
  - Black consumer market, 1982
  - California, 1983
  - Competition, 1982-1983
  - Hispanic consumer market, 1983-1984
  - Mid-America, 1983
  - Women consumers, 1980
  - Youth and college-age consumers, 1982-1985
- Ford Motor Company Studies Series, 1974-1989, (3 boxes)
  - General, 1976-1984, (3 folders)
  - Bronco, 1978-1984 (Box 2)
  - Escort, 1979-1989, (3 folders)
  - EXP, 1980-1986
  - Fairmont, 1976-1981
  - Fiesta, 1978-1987
  - Fox (Comet, Maverick), 1976-1979
  - Futura, 1977-1981 (Box 3)
  - Granada, 1976-1981
  - LTD, 1977-1984, (2 folders)
  - Mercury Capri, 1978
  - Mercury Marquis, 1978
  - Mustang, 1976-1984
  - Pickup
    - 4x2, 1978-1984
    - 4x4, 1976-1984 (Box 4)
  - Pinto, 1976-1979
  - Probe, 1988
  - Taurus, 1985-1986
  - Tempo/Topaz, 1981-1986, (2 folders)
  - Thunderbird, 1978-1988, (3 folders)
  - Vans, 1974-1981